I was raised in Seoul, Korea,
ترعرعت في مدينة سيول، بكوريا،
and moved to New York City in 1999 to attend college.
ومن ثم إنتقلت إلي نيويورك في عام 1999 للالتحاق بالجامعة.
I was pre-med at the time,
كنت وقتها في مرحلة الطب التمهيدية,
and I thought I would become a surgeon
وكنت أظن بأني سأصبح جراحة
because I was interested in anatomy
لأنني كنت مولعة بعلم التشريح
and dissecting animals really piqued my curiosity.
وتحديداً تشريح الحيوانات كان مثار فضولي.
At the same time, I fell in love with New York City.
في تلك اللحظات, وقعت في حب مدينة نيويورك.
I started to realize that I could look at the whole city
بدأت أدرك أنه بإمكاني إلتأمل في الشكل الكلي للمدينة
as a living organism.
بإعتبارها كائناً حياً.
I wanted to dissect it
راودتني الرغبة في تشريحها
and look into its unseen layers.
وتفحص كل ثناياها المخفية.
And the way to it, for me,
وكان السبيل إلي ذلك، بالنسبة لي،
was through artistic means.
يكمن في إستخدام الوسائل الفنية.
So, eventually I decided to pursue an MFA instead of an M.D.
فقررت مؤخراً أن أحضر الماجستير في الفنون الجميلة بدلا عن الطب.
and in grad school I became interested
وفي الدراسات العليا أصبحت مهتمة
in creatures that dwell in the hidden corners of the city.
بالكائنات التي تحيا في الأركان الخفية من المدينة.
In New York City, rats are part of commuters' daily lives.
في مدينة نيويورك، تعتبر الفئران بمثابة جزء من الحياة اليومية للمسافرين.
Most people ignore them or are frightened of them.
أغلب الناس يتجاهلونها او يرتعبون منها.
But I took a liking to them
لكني أعجبت بهم
because they dwell on the fringes of society.
لأنهم يحيون علي هامش المجتمع.
And even though they're used in labs to promote human lives,
وحتي علي الرغم من أنهم يستخدمون في المعامل لجعل حياة البشر أفضل،
they're also considered pests.
فأنهم أيضا يعتبرون آفات.
I also started looking around in the city
بدأت أيضا النظر داخل المدينة
and trying to photograph them.
ومحاولة إلتقاط صورهم.
One day, in the subway, I was snapping pictures of the tracks
يوماً ما, في مترو الأنفاق، كنت إلتقط صوراً للقضبان
hoping to catch a rat or two,
يراودني الأمل في إقتناص فأراً أو فأرين،
and a man came up to me and said,
فأقبل نحوي أحدهم وصاح،
"You can't take photographs here.
"لا يمكنك إلتقاط الصور هنا.
The MTA will confiscate your camera."
لأن هيئة النقل ستصادر آلة تصويرك."
I was quite shocked by that,
تلقيت صدمة قاسية من جراء ذلك,
and thought to myself, "Well, OK then.
وقلت في قرارة نفسي، "حسنا، وماذا بعد.
I'll follow the rats."
سأبدأ بمطاردة الفئران."
Then I started going into the tunnels,
ثم بدأت في النزول إلى داخل الأنفاق،
which made me realize that there's a whole new dimension to the city
الأمر الذي جعلني إستشعر بأن هنالك وجهاً متكاملاً جديداً للمدينة
that I never saw before and most people don't get to see.
لم يتسنى لي أن ألحظه من قبل ومعظهم كذلك.
Around the same time, I met like-minded individuals
خلال ذلك الوقت، صادفت أشخاص بنفس عقليتي
who call themselves urban explorers, adventurers, spelunkers,
كانوا يطلقون علي أنفسهم مستكشفي الحضر، مغامرون، مستكشفي الكهوف،
guerrilla historians, etc.
مؤرخي حرب العصابات، إلخ.
I was welcomed into this loose, Internet-based network
كنت محل ترحيب ضمن هذه الكوكبة, التي تتواصل عبر الإنترنيت
of people who regularly explore urban ruins
والمكونة من أشخاص يبحثون دوماً في أنقاض المدن
such as abandoned subway stations,
مثل محطات المترو المهجورة،
tunnels, sewers, aqueducts,
أنفاق، مجارير، قنوات،
factories, hospitals, shipyards and so on.
مصانع، مستشفيات، أحواض السفن وما إلي ذلك.
When I took photographs in these locations,
وبعد أن إلتقطت صوراً لهذه المواقع،
I felt there was something missing in the pictures.
أدركت بان هنالك شئٌ ما ينقصها.
Simply documenting these soon-to-be-demolished structures
ببساطة توثيق هذه الهياكل التي توشك علي الفناء
wasn't enough for me.
لم يكن مقنعاً بالنسبة لي.
So I wanted to create a fictional character
فأردت تصور شخصية خيالية
or an animal that dwells in these underground spaces,
أو حتى حيوان يقطن في تلك المناطق النفقية،
and the simplest way to do it, at the time,
ولعل من أيسر السبل لتحقيق ذلك في وقتها,
was to model myself.
كان عن طريق تصوير نفسي.
I decided against clothing
وقررت أن أكون ضد فكرة إرتداء الملابس
because I wanted the figure to be without any cultural implications
لأني أردت ألا يعكس الكائن الحي تبعاته الثقافية
or time-specific elements.
أو عوامل إرتباطه بالزمن.
I wanted a simple way to represent a living body
أردت طريقة بسيطة لتمثيل مخلوق حي
inhabiting these decaying, derelict spaces.
يقطن هذه المناطق المهجورة والمدمرة.
This was taken in the Riviera Sugar Factory in Red Hook, Brooklyn.
لقد تم إلتقاط هذه في مصنع الريفيرا للسكر في رد هوك، بروكلين.
It's now an empty, six-acre lot
هو الأن عبارة عن ستة هكتارات من الأراضي الخاوية
waiting for a shopping mall right across from the new Ikea.
والتي تقبع أمام محل تجاري قبالة محلات "أيكيا الجديدة"
I was very fond of this space
أعجبتني تلك المساحة كثيراً
because it's the first massive industrial complex I found on my own
لأنها بمثابة أول مجمع صناعي ضخم وجدته بمفردي
that is abandoned.
حيث كان مهجوراً.
When I first went in, I was scared,
وحينما ولجت إليه في البدء، كنت خائفة،
because I heard dogs barking and I thought they were guard dogs.
لأني سمعت أصوات كلاب تنبح وظننتها كلاب للحراسة.
But they happened to be wild dogs living there,
إلا أنها كانت كلاب متوحشة تأوي هناك
and it was right by the water,
تماماً بالقرب من إتجاه الميا,
so there were swans and ducks swimming around
لذا فقد كان يسبح فيها البط والبجع
and trees growing everywhere
وأشجار تنمو في كل مكان
and bees nesting in the sugar barrels.
والنحل يبني خلاياه في براميل السكر.
The nature had really reclaimed the whole complex.
لقد تمكنت الطبيعة بالفعل من إستصلاح المجمع بأكمله.
And, in a way, I wanted the human figure in the picture
و بطريقة ما، أردت إدراج العنصر البشري إلى الصورة
to become a part of that nature.
لتصبح جزء من تلك الطبيعة.
When I got comfortable in the space,
عندما شعرت بالطمأنينة في المكان،
it also felt like a big playground.
بدأت أتصوره كملعب شاسع.
I would climb up the tanks and hop across exposed beams
حيث يمكنني أن أتسلق في خزانات المياه لأقفز عبر أعمتده العارية
as if I went back in time and became a child again.
كأنما عاد الزمن بي لأصبح طفلة من جديد.
This was taken in the old Croton Aqueduct,
تم إلتقاط هذه الصورة في قناطر كروتون القديمة
which supplied fresh water to New York City for the first time.
التي أمدت مدينة نيويورك بالمياه النظيفة لأول مرة.
The construction began in 1837.
بدأت علميات الإنشاء في عام 1837م.
It lasted about five years.
والتي إمتدت لحوالي خمس سنوات.
It got abandoned when the new Croton Aqueducts opened in 1890.
وتم هجرها في عام 1890م عندما تم فتح قناطر كروتون الجديدة.
When you go into spaces like this,
فعندما تقصد أماكن كهذه,
you're directly accessing the past,
لن تلبث أن تجد نفسك قد ولجت مباشرة في الماضي
because they sit untouched for decades.
لأنها تظل على هي عليه لعقود.
I love feeling the aura of a space that has so much history.
يعجبني الشعور بعبق المكان المشبع بنفحات التاريخ.
Instead of looking at reproductions of it at home,
بدلاً من إلقاء نظرة على تلك الصور في المنزل،
you're actually feeling the hand-laid bricks
فيمكنك في الواقع تحسس الطوب المرصوف يدوياً
and shimmying up and down narrow cracks
وتتقافز هنا وهناك بفعل التصدعات الضيقة
and getting wet and muddy
وتبتل ويلوث ثيابك الوحل
and walking in a dark tunnel with a flashlight.
وتخطو في نفق مظلم بكشافك اليدوي.
This is a tunnel underneath Riverside Park.
هذا نفق أسفل "حديقة الريفر سايد".
It was built in the 1930s by Robert Moses.
تم حفره في ثلاثينيات القرن الماضي على يد روبرت موسيس.
The murals were done by a graffiti artist
وقام أحد فناني الرسم على الجدران بزخرفة جدرانه
to commemorate the hundreds of homeless people
للأحتفاء بذكري مئات من المشردين
that got relocated from the tunnel in 1991
الذين تم إخلائهم من النفق في 1991
when the tunnel reopened for trains.
عندما تم إعادة فتحه للقطارات.
Walking in this tunnel is very peaceful.
السير في هذا النفق مطمئن جداً.
There's nobody around you,
لا يوجد أحد حولك،
and you hear the kids playing in the park above you,
وتسمتع إلى الأطفال يلعبون بالحديقة فوقك،
completely unaware of what's underneath.
لا يعون تماماً ما بأسفل.
When I was going out a lot to these places,
عندما كنت أخرج كثيراً لهذه الأماكن
I was feeling a lot of anxiety and isolation
كنت أشعر بكثير من القلق والعزلة
because I was in a solitary phase in my life,
لأني كنت في مرحلة عزلة في حياتي
and I decided to title my series "Naked City Spleen,"
وقررت أن أعنون مجموعتي "طحال المدينة العارية"
which references Charles Baudelaire.
في إقتباس لتشارلز بودلير.
"Naked City" is a nickname for New York,
"المدينة العارية" هو كنية لنيويورك،
and "Spleen" embodies the melancholia and inertia
و"الطحال" يجسد الخمول والكمد
that come from feeling alienated in an urban environment.
التي جاءت عبر إحساس غريب عن البيئة الحضرية.
This is the same tunnel.
هذا هو نفس النفق.
You see the sunbeams coming from the ventilation ducts
تلحظون أشعة الشمس تتسلل عبر نوافذ التهوية
and the train approaching.
ويشارف القطار على الوصول.
This is a tunnel that's abandoned in Hell's Kitchen.
هذا هو النفق المهجور المضمن في برنامج "هيلز كيتشين"
I was there alone, setting up,
كنت هناك بمفردي، أتجهز،
and a homeless man approached.
وشخص مشرد إقترب مني.
I was basically intruding in his living space.
كنت أتطفل علي مكان سكنه.
I was really frightened at first,
كنت مرعوبة في البداية،
but I calmly explained to him that I was working on an art project
إلا أني أوضحت له بهدوء عن أنني أقوم بعمل فني
and he didn't seem to mind
ولم يبدو عليه الإعتراض
and so I went ahead and put my camera on self-timer
لذا واصلت عملي وضبطت آلة تصويري على المؤقت الذاتي
and ran back and forth.
وركضت منها وإليها.
And when I was done, he actually offered me his shirt
وعندما إنتهيت، عرض علي قميصه
to wipe off my feet
لمسح الوحل من أقدامي
and kindly walked me out.
وبلطف إصطحبني إلى الخارج.
It must have been a very unusual day for him.
لابد أنه كان يوم غير عادي جداً له.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
One thing that struck me, after this incident,
شيء واحد لفت نظري ، بعد هذه الواقعة ،
was that a space like that holds so many deleted memories of the city.
هوأن مكان كهذا يحوي الكثير من ذكريات المدينة الممحوة
That homeless man, to me, really represented
هذا الرجل المشرد، بالنسبة لي، يمثل في الواقع
an element of the unconscious of the city.
عنصر اللاوعي في هذه المدينة.
He told me that he was abused above ground
أخبرني أن هنالك من أساء إليه في الأعلى,
and was once in Riker's Island,
وكان يوماً من سكان جزيرة ريكر،
and at last he found peace and quiet in that space.
وأخيرا وجد الأمان والهدوء في هذا المكان.
The tunnel was once built for the prosperity of the city,
لقد تم إنشاء هذا النفق للإسهام في إذدهار المدينة,
but is now a sanctuary for outcasts,
ولكنه الأن ملاذا للمنبوذين،
who are completely forgotten in the average urban dweller's everyday life.
الذين هم منسيين تماماً من الحياة اليومية لقاطني الحضر
This is underneath my alma mater, Columbia University.
هذه أسفل كليتي ، جامعة كولومبيا.
The tunnels are famous for having been used
الأنفاق مشهورة لاستخدامها
during the development of the Manhattan Project.
خلال تطوير مشروع منهاتن.
This particular tunnel is interesting
هذا النفق تحديداً مثير للأهتمام
because it shows the original foundations of Bloomingdale Insane Asylum,
لأنه يظهر الأساسات الأصلية لمصحة بلومنجديل العقلية
which was demolished in 1890
الذي تم هدمها في 1890
when Columbia moved in.
عندما إنتقلت كولومبيا للمكان.
This is the New York City Farm Colony,
وهذه مزرعة كولوني في مدينة نيويورك،
which was a poorhouse in Staten Island
التي كانت إصلاحية في جزيرة ستاتن
from the 1890s to the 1930s.
من تسعينيات القرن التاسع عشر إلي ثلاثينيات القرن العشرين.
Most of my photos are set in places
أغلب صوري كانت في الأماكن
that have been abandoned for decades,
التي تم هجرها لعقود
but this is an exception.
ولكن هذه إستثناء
This children's hospital was closed in 1997;
مستشفي الأطفال هذه أغلقت في 1997م:
it's located in Newark.
تقع في مدينة نيو آرك:
When I was there three years ago,
عندما كنت هناك منذ ثلاث سنوات،
the windows were broken and the walls were peeling,
كانت النوافذ مكسورة والحوائط مقشرة،
but everything was left there as it was.
ولكن كل شيء كان متروكاً كما هو.
You see the autopsy table, morgue trays, x-ray machines
ترون منضدة التشريح، طاولات المشرحة، ماكينات أشعة إكس
and even used utensils,
وحتي الأدوات المستعملة
which you see on the autopsy table.
التي ترونها علي منضدة التشريح.
After exploring recently-abandoned buildings,
بعد إستكشاف المباني المهجورة حديثاً
I felt that everything could fall into ruins very fast:
شعرت أن كل شيء من الممكن أن يتحول إلي أطلال بمنتهي السرعة:
your home, your office, a shopping mall, a church --
منزلك، مكتبك، سوق تجاري، كنيسة...
any man-made structures around you.
أي شيء بناه الإنسان من حولك.
I was reminded of how fragile our sense of security is
الأمر الذي أثار تعجبي من هشاشة شعورنا بالطمأنينة
and how vulnerable people truly are.
وكم هي الناس ضعيفة.
I love to travel,
أنا مولع بالتسفار,
and Berlin has become one of my favorite cities.
وبرلين أصبحت واحدة من مدني المفضلة.
It's full of history,
إنها مليئة بالتاريخ،
and also full of underground bunkers
وأيضاً مليئة بالمخابيء تحت الأرض
and ruins from the war.
وأطلال من الحرب.
This was taken under a homeless asylum
هذه تم أخذها أسفل مأوي للمشردين
built in 1885 to house 1,100 people.
بني في 1885م لأيواء 1100 شخص.
I saw the structure while I was on the train,
رأيت البناء عندما كنت في القطار،
and I got off at the next station and met people there
وعندما نزلت في المحطة التالية وقابلت الناس هناك
that gave me access to their catacomb-like basement,
الذين أدخلوني الي بدرومهم الذي يشبه المدفن،
which was used for ammunition storage during the war
والذي كان يستخدم لتخزين الذخيرة خلال الحرب
and also, at some point, to hide groups of Jewish refugees.
وأيضا، في وقت ما، لأخفاء مجموعات من اللاجئين اليهود.
This is the actual catacombs in Paris.
هذه المقابر الحقيقية في باريس.
I explored there extensively
بحثت هناك بإستفاضة
in the off-limits areas
في المناطق المحظورة
and fell in love right away.
ووقعت في الحب مباشرة.
There are more than 185 miles of tunnels,
هناك أكثر من 185 ميل من الأنفاق
and only about a mile is open to the public as a museum.
وفقط حوالي ميل واحد مفتوح للعامة كمتحف.
The first tunnels date back to 60 B.C.
أول الأنفاق ترجع إلي 60 قبل الميلاد
They were consistently dug as limestone quarries
كانوا يحفرون بصفة مستمرة كمحاجر للحجر الجيري
and by the 18th century,
وبحلول القرن الثامن عشر،
the caving-in of some of these quarries posed safety threats,
إنهيارات بعض هذه المحاجر شكل مخاطر للسلامة
so the government ordered reinforcing of the existing quarries
لذا أمرت الحكومة بتدعيم المحاجر الموجودة
and dug new observation tunnels
وحفر أنفاق مراقبة جديدة
in order to monitor and map the whole place.
لمراقبة ووضع خريطة للمكان.
As you can see, the system is very complex and vast.
كما ترون، النظام معقد جداً وضخم.
It's very dangerous to get lost in there.
أنه لمن الخطير أن تتوه بداخله.
And at the same time,
وفي نفس الوقت،
there was a problem in the city with overflowing cemeteries.
كانت هناك مشكلة في المدينة لأنتشار المدافن.
So the bones were moved from the cemeteries into the quarries,
لذا تم نقل العظام من المقابر إلي المحاجر،
making them into the catacombs.
وتحويلها إلي مدافن.
The remains of over six million people are housed in there,
رفات أكثر من ستة ملايين شخص ترقد بداخلها.
some over 1,300 years old.
بعضها عمره أكثر من 1300 عام.
This was taken under the Montparnasse Cemetery
وقد أخذت هذه تحت مقبرة مونتبارناس
where most of the ossuaries are located.
حيث توجد معظم التوابيت الصغيرة.
There are also phone cables that were used in the '50s
توجد أيضا كابلات تليفونات كانت تستخدم في الخمسينات.
and many bunkers from the World War II era.
ومخابيء عديدة من زمن الحرب العالمية الثانية.
This is a German bunker.
هذا مخبأ ألماني.
Nearby there's a French bunker,
يوجد بالقرب منه مخبأ فرنسي،
and the whole tunnel system is so complex
ونظام الأنفاق ككل معقد للغاية
that the two parties never met.
لدرجة أن المخبأين لم يتقاطعا البتة.
The tunnels are famous for having been used by the Resistance,
الأنفاق مشهورة لأستخدامها بواسطة المقاومة،
which Victor Hugo wrote about in "Les Miserables."
التي كتب عنها فيكتور هوجو في رواية البؤساء.
And I saw a lot of graffiti from the 1800s, like this one.
ورأيت كثير من الجداريات من القرن التاسع عشر، مثل هذه.
After exploring the underground of Paris,
بعد إستكشاف ما تحت باريس،
I decided to climb up,
قررت التسلق لأعلي،
and I climbed a Gothic monument
وتسلقت النصب القوطي
that's right in the middle of Paris.
هذا بالضبط في وسط باريس.
This is the Tower of Saint Jacques.
هذا برج القديس جاك.
It was built in the early 1500s.
تم بناءه في بدايات القرن السادس عشر.
I don't recommend sitting on a gargoyle in the middle of January, naked.
أنا لا أنصح يالجلوس على حوض مياه في منتصف يناير ، عاريا.
It was not very comfortable. (Laughter)
كان غير مريح بالمرة.
And all this time,
وطول ذلك الوقت,
I never saw a single rat in any of these places,
لم أر فأراً واحداً في أي من هذه الأماكن،
until recently, when I was in the London sewers.
حتي قريباً، عندما كنت في مجاري لندن.
This was probably the toughest place to explore.
والتي على الأرجح كانت إقسى مناطق الإستكشاف.
I had to wear a gas mask because of the toxic fumes --
كان علي إرتداء قناع للغاز، بسبب الغازات السامة،
I guess, except for in this picture.
أظن فيما عدا تلك الصورة.
And when the tides of waste matter come in
وحين تأتي إلي موجات مواد النفايات
it sounds as if a whole storm is approaching you.
تبدو كأن عاصفة بأكملها قادمة بإتجاهك.
This is a still from a film I worked on recently, called "Blind Door."
هذه لقطة من فيلم كانت أعمل به قريبا، يسمي الباب الأعمي.
I've become more interested in capturing movement and texture.
أصبحت أكثر إهتماماً بتسجيل الحركة والملمس.
And the 16mm black-and-white film gave a different feel to it.
و الفيلم الـ 16 ملم الأبيض والأسود أعطاني إحساس مختلف بها.
And this is the first theater project I worked on.
وهذا أول مشروع مسرحي عملت به.
I adapted and produced "A Dream Play" by August Strindberg.
أعددت للمسرح وأنتجت "مسرحية الحلم" لـ أوجست ستريندبرج
It was performed last September one time only
وعرضت سبتمبر الماضي لمرة واحدة فقط
in the Atlantic Avenue tunnel in Brooklyn,
في نفق شارع الأطلانتيك في بروكلين،
which is considered to be the oldest underground train tunnel in the world,
والذي يعتبر أقدم أنفاق القطارات تحت الأرض في العالم،
built in 1844.
تم حفره في عام 1844م.
I've been leaning towards more collaborative projects like these, lately.
كنت أميل نحو المشروعات المشتركة كهذه، مؤخراً.
But whenever I get a chance I still work on my series.
لكن كلما حانت الفرصة فأني أعمل في سلسلتي.
The last place I visited
أخر مكان زرته
was the Mayan ruins of Copan, Honduras.
كان أطلال المايا في كوبان، هندوراس.
This was taken inside an archaeological tunnel in the main temple.
هذه قد تم إلتقاطها في نفق اثري في المعبد الرئيسي.
I like doing more than just exploring these spaces.
أحب أن افعل ما هو أكثر من إستكشاف هذه الأماكن.
I feel an obligation to animate and humanize these spaces continually
أحس بألتزام لتحريك وإضفاء الإنسانية علي هذه الأماكن بشكل مستمر
in order to preserve their memories in a creative way --
من أجل الحفاظ علي ذكرياتها بطريقة إبداعية
before they're lost forever.
قبل أن نفقدها للأبد.
Thank you.
شكراً لكم